ILGWU Justice Photographs 5780/102 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Local 89 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Includes: Parade with Local 89 float, 10/15/59; Italian American Labor Council, John Gelo treasurer, Emma Lucchi, Joseph Procopi - VP, Luigi Antonini - President, A. Campobasso - VP, Jay Lovestone - guest speaker, and Howard Molisani - secretary, 12/15/53; Luigi Antonini with Pope Paul VI, no date; VP Salvatore Noto, general secretary of Local 89, acknowledges award presented to him by Deborah Heart and Lung Care Center at dinner-dance, with Mrs. Noto and President and Mrs. Stulberg, 4/123/74; Members of Italian Dressmakers' Local 89 proudly marching along Fifth Avenue during annual Columbus Day Parade, New York City, 11/1/60; First VP Luigi Antonini chats with Italian Social Democratic leader Giuseppe Saragat who is waiting to speak to the Italian-American community over the "Voice at Local 89," with Joseph Lupis, Italian Undersecretary of Foreign Affairs for Immigration, and Salvatore Noto, assistant manager of Italian Dressmakers' Local 89, 3/1/68; First VP Luigi Antonini, Local 89 general secretary, extends appreciation to Dr. Vito LaRocca eminent eye surgeon, for humanitarian action helping Mrs. Asaro and her child, with VP E. Howard Molisani, manager of Italian Cloakmakers Local 48, and Salvatore Noto, assistant general secretary of Local 89, 11//15/62; On behalf of ILGWU, First VP Luigi presents check for $25,000 to President Giuseppe Saragat of the Republic of Italy, with Vanni B. Montana, editor of Giustzia, and contingent of garment unionists traveling in Italy on Local 89 sponsored tour, 6/15/67; In the traditional Columbus Day parade along Fifth Avenue in new York are ILGWU First VP Luigi Antonini - General Secretary of Italian Dressmakers Local 89, VP E. Howard Molisani - Manager of Italian Cloakmakers Local 48, and Salvatore Noto - Local 89 assistant manager secretary, 10/15/67; Frank Longo, newly names assistant manager of Italian Dressmakers Local 89 with VP Salvatore Noto, local manager - general secretary, at organization office, 3/1/69; Italy's President Giuseppe Saragat welcomes ILGWU VP Salvatore Noto Local 89 managers and a group of 136 local members and their families at a reception in the presidential palace in Rome, 8/15/69; Local 89 members getting off a bus, Sept. 1980
- Local 89 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  Includes: Local 48 bids adieu to Italian visitor: Luigi Nardi - Italian Council General, Frank Comunale -assistant manager Local 48, Senator Mario Cingolani - Head of the Italian Delegation of the International labor Conference at San Francisco, and M. Danzella - President of Local 48; Luigi Antonini, no date; Luigi Antonini in congress, 6/12/57; Luigi Antonini, no date; Luigi Antonini, no date; Luigi Antonini, no date; Luigi Antonini, William Green, J Hochman, no date; First radio campaign talk for Mayor F. Pecora is congratulated by John Gelo of Local 89, 9/23/50; Luigi Antonini with children, no date; Italian American Labor Council: Louis Nelson Local 155, Julius Hochman - International Joint Board Manager, Edna List Weber - director of Carla Tresco Institute, Luigi Antonini - chair, Angelica Bolabianoff, Dr. Edmond Cossu - Director of Labor Ministry Division in Italy and Howard Molisani of Local 48, 7/20/50; Luigi Antonini, no date; Bombace, no date Luigi Antonini, no date, Luigi Antonini, no date
- Local 89 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Includes: Sol Chaikin and Louis Stulberg, no date; Mr. and Mrs. John Gelo departing for Europe at La Guardia Airport, 4/14/46; Luigi Antonini speaking at rally in Milan, no date; Luigi Antonini and David Dubinsky, no date; Luigi Antonini (2 copies), no date; Mr. and Mrs. John Gelo, no date; Three Presidential elections express their happiness upon President Roosevelt's reelection at ALP, Comm. Joseph V. O'Leary, Luigi Antonini and Alex Rose, no date; Local 89 Installation Ceremony, with Antonini, Gelo, Dubinsky and others, metropolitan Opera House, 4/1/50; John Gelo and others, no date; Lt. Gen. Mark Clark, CG Fifth Army, greets US and English labor men visiting Fifth Army Hats, with Luigi Antonini - AFL, George Baldanzi - CIO, and Thomas O'Brien and Will Lawther, of Br. Trade Union Congress, Florence Area, Italy, 7/19/44; Gelo, Charles Zimmerman, Luigi Antonini, Julius Hochman, no date; John Gelo, no date; William Green, Luigi Antonini, George Meany
- Local 89 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Includes: Angela Bambace, no date; Mercedes Donald, no date; Antonini with many others outside a bus, no date; Students with Roosevelt sign, no date; Athletic team with Mondello sign, no date; Frances Camarda, no date; Antonini, Mr. and Mrs. Dubinsky, John Gelo, no date; Sol Chaikin and Mario Cuomo, no date; Crowd scene, no date
- Local 91 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Includes: VP Harry Greenberg, manager of New York Children's Dressmakers' Local 91, addresses a large meeting of shop representatives, Roosevelt Auditorium, no date; Veteran business agent Morris Berkowitz of NY Children's Dressmakers' Local 91 is honored on his retirement, with VP Harry Greenberg - Local 91 manager, Mrs. Berkowitz, and Business Agent Ray Orsini, 2/1/60; Local 91 art class, no date; Local 91 members on strike against Cotton Fair, no date; Following graduation exercises at High School of Fashion Industries on June 7, 1966, Edward Schneider, manager of New York Children's Dressmakers' Local 91, with ILGers holding certificates of achievement with Larry Birch, Local 32 business agent, 6/7/66; Manager Edward Schneider Children's Dressmakers' Local 91, presents local's first maternity benefits to Ramona Tejeda and Isabella Rodriguez Batista with gift blanket held by grandmother, 3/15/68; Mrs. Louis Stulberg, Edward Schneider, manager of Children's Dressmakers' local 91, and Marcelle Burnham, fashion editor of Parents Magazine, at children's fashion parade, no date; Raymond Orsini greeted by local Manager Edward Schneider as Business agent of New York Children's Dressmakers' Local 91 at an event honoring Orsini on his retirement, with grandchildren John and Raymond Castranaro, 2/1/68; Local 91 Manager Edward Schneider leads Local 91 nominating meeting, 2/1/71; Louis Stulberg speaking, no date
- Local 98 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  Includes: Local 98 members listen attentively as Manager Pokodner speaks at nominating meeting, Roosevelt Auditorium, 2/1/71; Herbert Pokodner, Local 98 Manager, presents union demand to employer representatives across the table during start of negotiations with staffers Herbert Gershon and Sol Pesserib, and local President Seymour Seiden, 2/15/69; Columbia Plastics Co. workers on strike for affiliation with new York Plastic Workers Local 98, 2/15/61
- Local 55 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  Includes: Local 99 members and workers of Land-N-Sea Diplomat Spts., 9/1/62; Mayor John V. Lyndsay is escorted into shop meeting of members of New York Office and Distribution Workers; Local 99 by Manager Douglas Levin, 11/1/66; Douglas Levin, manager of NY Local 99 details terms of new contract with members of Local's negotiating committee, 7/1/66; VP Douglas Levin asks for a show of hands during Local 99 nominating meeting, 2/5/71
- Local 102 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  Includes: Pact '102' Meeting contact sheets, At signing of pact between Gilbert Carriers of Secaucus, New Jersey and Local 102 were organizer George Jackson, Abe Schlesinger - union attorney, George Irvine Local 102 manager, Sam Schor - Gilbert President, Lawrence Milman - company counsel, Business Agent Nat Newman - shop committee member Carlos Perez, Theodore Gusalnick - shop steward, committee member Arcadrio Cochran, Don Buchalter - company attorney, Business Agent Joe Davis, no date; Local 102 Manager George Irvine congratulates George Jackson on his rapid promotion to business agent, 5/1/70; Manager George Irvine swears in "rookie" executive board members who were elected at nominating meeting in new York's Hotel Diplomat, with Bertha Shorts (Nelson Resources), Obie Wells (National) Packing, Allen Shapiro (Merit Dress Delivery), Ronnie Blake (Empire Carriers) 2/1/71
- Local 105 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  Includes: Members of New York Local 105 picket Morton Karten showrooms at 520 8th Avenue, 6/15/61; Dubinsky and Mayor Lyndsay, no date; Ship representatives vote approval of NY Local 105 contract terms, with Manager Martin L. Cohen, 6/1/67; Workers from Local 105 contracting shops hear Manager Martin L. Cohen report at Manhattan Center meeting, 6/15/67; Chinese members of local 10 turned out to hear Manager Martin L. Cohen detail health and welfare benefits during meeting in Most Sacred Blood Church as Chinatown's Baxter Street, with Assistant Manager Henry Prastien, Irving Schoenwald director of organization in the area, and Business Agent Harris Zinn who services Chinatown Shops, no date
- Local 132 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  Includes: Nicholas Chydai receives check from Sheldon Edelman, Executive Director of the Plastic Products Manufacturers Association at ceremony held on Jan. 9, 1966 at New York Local 132 headquartered making payment of pension checks to first 10 local retirees, with Murray Gross Manager of Local 66 and Joel Menist, local 132 manager, 1/15/62; Joel Menist, manager of Local 132, presents union demands to employers in first negotiating session, with some of Local's negotiating team, 6/15/70, Local 132 Manager Joel Menist about contract negotiations, no date; Local 132 signing of contract, no date
- Local 132 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  Includes: Organizing director Eddie Nesbit and staffers Elba Reyes, Jimmy Gonzalez, and Leo Suarez and worker Willie George on picket line for strike against Emsee Labs, 12/15/74; Manager Sam Eisenberg of Local 132 and negotiations with Local amp; Plastic Molders, Metal amp; Novelty Manufacturers representatives, 5/1/76; President Alexander King chairs union meeting where Manager Sam Eisenberg is reelected, 2/1/77; Picket scene of workers on strike against Temp. Jewelry Inc., 5/1/77
- Local 155 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  Includes: Vice President Sol Greene of Local 155 gives speech on talks of obtaining CORA increase, 7/1/74; Sol Greene and strikers raising hands; W7W workers on picketline during strike called because the firm refused to recognize the local as the union; Impartial Chairman George Mintzer hears case between Local 155 &; United Knitwear Manufacturers League, Sol Greene presented union's case &; Lazare Teper presented economic data, 8/1/74; Dr. Lilly Bruck, Director of Consumer Education for NYC speaks to local 155 leadership institute at Columbia University while Sol Greene stands and looks on, 8/15/74; Organizing Director Norman Lewis hands out leaflets in an organizing effort in Brooklyn, 2/1/75; Sol Greene shakes hand with assistant chairlady Maria Ramos, Elsa Mosquerra, Knitting Department Chairlady is there and Business Agent Israel Camacho looks on, 4/15/75; Union defenders leaflet before work, 5/1/76; At Local 155's annual Christmas party for members children organizer Violeta Putterman hands out gift, 12/15/76; Sol Green posing with newly elected officers, Edward Geltzer was reelected assistant manager standing to right, 2/1/77; Sol Green FIT curriculum with five students, 4/15/77; Member Dorothy Council writes a letter at home to Jimmy Carter, 5/1/77; Banner "In Union There Is Strength, Fair Trade Not Free Trade" in a parade, Oct. 1981
- Local 155 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  Includes: Labor Division chairman Harry Van Arsdale Jr. is presented with a dimes contribution by Vice President Louis Nelson, 11/15/60; Workers often different nationalities at a year-end party at Lee Mar Company (Czechoslovakia, Germany, Lithuania, Poland, Hungary, China, Israel, Puerto Rico, Galicia and US), 2/1/61; VP Louis Nelson presents union demands to section meeting of NY Knitgoods workers Local 155, 6/1/61; Ratification meeting in Manhattan Center lead by Louis Nelson, 8/1/61; Mayor Wagner addressing Local 155 with Louis Nelson as chair of meeting, 11/1/61; President Sol Chaikin swears in Norman Lewis as manager of 155 and Business Agent Lydia Ramos, Feb. 1982; Bust of Jose Marti and Cuban flag presented to Louis Nelson, also pictured Armando Alexander, Miguel Ruano, Nelson, Oscar Prieto, Lucio Sanchez, and Orlando Cardelle, 7/15/65; Louis Nelson addresses membership meeting, 5/15/66; Label Committee headed by Sarah Rose distributing leaflets at Brooklyn, Brighton Beach, 8/1/66; Louis Nelson details new demands to membership with Sol Gross, local president and Louis Levinson, assistant manager, 6/15/67; Louis Nelson speaks to membership, 2/15/68; 50 members of NY Knitgoods Workers in front of plane going to Mexico, 3/1/68; Louis Nelson reports to shop chairman, 1/1/69; Louis Nelson extends best wishes to successor Sol Greene at meeting, also pictured Sol Gross, Local President, ILGWU President Louis Stulberg, Louis Levinson, Local Assistant Manager, 9/15/69; Brooklyn Derby Textile Workers picket for strike, 5/1/70; Picketline and strike of workers at Abaco Fabrics, 6/1/70; Manager Greene is congratulated by workers, 8/1/70; Sol Greene addressing membership with Charles Zimmerman vice President and Louis Levinson, assistant manager, 8/1/70; Picket line against Z &; Z Sportswear, 9/1/70; Andrew Imutan, President of United Farm Workers receives check from Sol Greene as Levinson looks on, 9/15/70; Introductions of nominees at local meeting, 2/15/71; Members of Local 155 await turn to vote, 3/1/71; Local members depositing ballots, 3/1/71; Members lined up at polling place, 3/1/71; At Textile Specialty Shop Chairman Eliezer Diaz signing a petition as Business Agent Lydia Ramos points the way, 5/1/71; Vote registration and counting of the ballots of the locals elections, 4/1/72; Lois Levinson drops by recent executive board meeting, Manager Sol Greene gives him a handshake as Edward Geltzer looks on, 12/15/72; Picket line outside W &; W's showroom of the parent firm House of Knitting, 8/1/74; Election committee member signs tally sheet certifying ballots, no date; President Louis Nelson reports on status of renewal talks at Unity House, no date; Vice President Louis Nelson presents union demands with Union team Murray Handler, Berg &; Berg chairman, Business Agent Dan Ielardi, Assistant Manager Louis Levinson, Manger Nelson, lawyers Elias Leiberman and Aaron Katz, Arthur Jacobson Local organizing director, and Frank Bauman, no date
- Midwest Region (Box 19, Folder 17)
  Includes: Presentation of Histadrut Award to Morris Bialis Chicago, June 20, 1959 with Pat Gorman - Sectary-Treasurer of Amalgamated Meat Cutter, Lois Stulberg General Secretary-Treasurer ILGWU, Morris Bialis Vice President ILGWU, William A. Lee President Chicago Federation of Labor and Julius Ginsberg, 7/1/59; Local 206 members picket Jeanette Frocks in Minneapolis (included in photo are Lucille Waldera, Adele Molitor, Ethel Rhiners, Irene Bowerman, Dolores Johnson (manager local), Leone Erion, Mary Davis, Judith Arme, Tressie Martin, Genevieve Scott and chairlady Emily Shurts), no date; banner "ILGWU supports Kennedy" holding banner are: Jimmy Schwartz, Assistant Director Harold Schwartz, Harry Rufer, Norbert Liesel, and Richard Zwerback 11/15/60; Bennie Brown, Executive Director of the Chicago Conference for Brotherhood looks on as Tom Mboya, African laborite shakes hands with Vice President Bialis, 3/15/62; First regional education conference at center desk are Harold Schwartz - Assistant Director of Region, Vice President Morris Bialis - Regional Director and Evelyn Dubrow, Executive Director of ILGWU Political Department; L. Axelrod, President of Local 5 and Vice President of Chicago Joint Board is honored at his 65th Birthday party by Federation of Jewish Trades Unions (Bialis hands him award), 3/24/62; Vice President Morris Bialis, Director of Midwest Region, greets George Paris who has retired and Raymond Machajeski, President of Local 188 in Milwaukee, 8/15/62; Martha Hill and Jean Copeland, Local 491 members picket during a McLoughlin Manufacturing Company Strike, 5/1/62; Ann Kacyar Sharron Eubanks, La Donna Dismaro, Alcetha Farlow ad Frances Mosley on a float in the Tri-County Day parade, 10/1/63; Henry Peterson and Local 486 member Loretta Lutes man an ILGWU union label booth at the Du Quoin State Fair, 10/1/63; Celebration marking 50th Anniversary of Labor Department with Vice President Morris Bialis, Labor Secretary W. Willard Wirtz, Reuben Soderstrom head of Illinois AFL-CIO, Congressman Roman Fucinski and Paul Iaccino Assistant to President of Chicago, 4/15/63; At Illinois State AFL-CIO Convention in Chicago Senator Paul Douglas is greeted by Assistant Regional Director Harold Schwartz, Linda Smith Midwest Region union label activities director and Vice President Morris Bialis, 11/1/63; Midwest ILGWU picket Marathon Rubber Products in Wau Saw, WI, 8/1/64; Vice President Morris Bialis and Governor Otto Kerner of Illinois at a meeting, 8/1/64; President David Dubinsky addressing staffers and Executive Board members of Chicago Locals at Midwest Region headquarters, on stage Harold Schwartz and Vice President Morris Bialis, 8/15/64; Vice President Morris Bialis, Midwest Region Director and Jacob Siegal, chairman of the Jewish Labor Committee congratulate A. Phillip Randolph on his award from the Labor Conference on Civil Rights, 12/1/64; Roly-Poly Pickets Chicago black woman, no date
- Midwest Region (Box 19, Folder 18)
  Includes: Bialis, Harold Schwartz and Mayor Richard Daley, 12/15/64; Mabel Terry and Leona Siman picket in front of More Manufacturing Company in Marissa, IL, 12/1/65; Local 436 of DeKalb, IL celebrates 20th Anniversary with Myrael Smith charter member, Harry Rufer general organizer, Edna Letheby local Vice President, Harold Schwartz Assistant Director of Midwest Region, Frances Kates local Financial Secretary, Michael Cannell Secretary of Fox Valley District Council, Gladys Steward local recording secretary, Minnie Lane - charter member, Charles Stark former President of Fox Valley Council, Stanley Hegland - President of Local, and Bob Dale, 5/15/66; Members of locals from Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Iowa and Wisconsin attend Midwest Region Institute at University of Wisconsin in Madison, 8/15/66; Illinois Democratic Senator Paul H. Douglas is greeted by Morris Bialis, 10/15/66; Local 529 ladies hold signs in favor of Senator Paul Douglas, Nelida Justiana, Doris Valesquez, Cleo Koley, Pat Weeks, Joan Freides, Mary Lee Gordon, Letty Cobb, Virgie Hood, Elaine Staffeldt, Ilona Schroarer, Velma Gabon, Beulah Lawther, Mary Bolton, Evalyn Talbot, 10/15/66; Mr. And Mrs. Bialis at a celebration of their 50th Wedding Anniversary, 2/1/68; Morris Bialis welcomes Cesar Chavez, United Farm Workers director at a luncheon, 12/1/69; Alvin Cloud, Della Lowe - Local 553 President, Lyle Greendeer - Committee member, Walter C. Kohlhoff committee chairman, ILGWU representatives and Donald Kret ILGWU Organizer, 7/1/70; Chicago Mayor Richard Daley greets Vice president Morris Bialis and William Lee, President of Chicago Federation of Labor at McCormick Place, 3/3/71; Morris Bialis, surrounded by Rolf A. Weil, President of Roosevelt University and Jerome Stone, chairman of the Board of Trustees is presented with honorary trustee status, 9/15/73; ILGWU members attend ILGWU School for workers at University of Illinois, 9/1/75; President Sol Chaikin receives plaque from Abe Rufus, President of Decatur, IL Local 120, 10/1/75; Vice President Morris Bialis speaks with Bernice Perry of AFL-CIO Community Services Department and Lou Montenegro Midwest Region Director at the labor conference on Civil Rights in Chicago, 1/1/79; Midwest Region Director Lou Montenegro makes a point to representatives of Smoler Brothers, also included is Vice President Nicholas Bonanno and Maurice Rosenstadt of Smoler Brothers, 6/79; Vice President Morris Bialis greets Adlai E. Stevenson III at meeting of Chicago Federation of Labor, no date; Executive Vice President Fredrick Siems, Vice President Lou Montenegro and staffers of the Midwest Region discuss contract negotiations, 4/82; Chicago Mayor Jane Byrne receives a plaque from Lou Montenegro and sews a union label on a jacket as she becomes an honorary member, 2/83; Oscar Sanchez is introduced as new Midwest organizing director at a staff meeting included are General Secretary-Treasurer Jay Mazur, Lou Montenegro and Sanchez, 10/83
- Miscellaneous (Box 19, Folder 19)
  Includes: People talking in a run-down house, no date; Someone giving a cashier food stamps, no date; Someone building a house, no date; Two young girls receiving a cafeteria lunch, no date; Local 596 Pam Lauplein and Alexander "Truckers" Vickers, 11/80; Picture of a boat, De Bogota, no date; Ollie Smith, Eunice Bates, Susie Walker, Gladys Boone and Melrose Slaughter congratulate Peyton on his ordination to ministry, 6/3/82; Editor Takeki Ijichi from Weekly Japanese labor News discussing with Zohv and Sevueiolg, 11/82; Mario Cuomo presenting plaque to Sol Chaikin, no date; And other unidentified photographs, no date
- New England (Box 19, Folder 20)
  Includes: Helen I've takes oath as business agent for Boston Joint Board from New England Director Ronald Alman as Manager Milton Kaplan looks on- 5/81; Manager Harvey Gold, district council president Walter Gaul, Local 24 Manager Julia Kamel present Julieta Velez, Effie Paikos Emmanuel Pensa with scholarships includes- New England director Ronald Alman-9/81; Senator Edward M. Kennedy speaks at Boston press conference with ILGWU Vice President Ronald Alman, New England director looks on-11/82; Vice President Ronald Alman on a pro-labor cable TV program-4/85; General Secretary- Treasurer Jay Mazur addresses New England Region staff meeting with Vice President Ron Alman looking on-3/84
- New Jersey (Box 19, Folder 21)
  Includes: Nancy Davila; Josefina Tamayo are given checks by Vice President Sol Goldberg, general manager of the region and Bergen-Hudson Manager Al Tambre 6/4/82; welcoming new assistant managers Christine Kerber and Carment Chaparro are Bergen-Hudson Manager Eli Charne, Vice President and Regional Director Sol Goldberg and Passaic Manager Dino Rinaldi- 7/22/85
- Pauline Newman (Box 19, Folder 22)
  Includes: posed portrait; group photo, circa 1914
- Norma Rae (Box 19, Folder 23)
  Includes: photograph of Sally Field playing Norma Rae; her mentor played by Ron Leibman; Sally Field as Norma Rae protesting conditions in textile plant- being carried off by cops; Norma Rae confides with parents played by Barbara Baxley and Pat Hingle; Norma Rae holding up a "union" sign-5/1/79
- Northeast Department (Box 19, Folder 24)
  Includes: David Gingold, Major John Kane, Fredrick Siems, William Lynch posed; Jack Halpern at Installation; Officers of Local 178 say farewell- Emily Conte- secretary, President Lucy Levesque, Ross, and Katherine Perron- treasurer; strike committee of Susquehanna Mills meet- Paul Border, chairman, Andrew Dermody, Mike Johnson at New Cumberland, PA; Mayor Dave Gingold, Jack Halpern, Mary Levin, Alfred Lacava, Anthony Genova, Santo Antonucci conference; Sol Greene explains ILGWU show "Get Happy" to President Warren Schadt and Treasurer Clyde Bishoff; Springfield Conference Massachusetts- Adolph Held, Phil Kramer, Fred Frank, David Gingold, A. Mercau, Jack Halpern, Louise DelMonte, William Ross and George Roewor 11/9/46; Retirements in Easton PA- Jack Halpern, Wilma Kaiser, president- Easton District, Norma Fenner and Margaret Smith- retired members, David Gingold; Grace Birkel-6/15/54; David Gingold and David Dubinsky with gavel in hand; Gus Tyler with WFDC Radio; several pictures of people rehearsing for a play
- Northeast Dept. - this folder was empty (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Northeast Department (Box 20, Folder 2)